Finding aid for the Machado and Silvetti Getty Villa renovation design records, 1994-2004 IA10019
Institutional Records and Archives
Getty Villa renovation design records
1994-2004
Institutional Records and Archives
Machado and Silvetti Associates, Inc
J. Paul Getty Museum
Getty Villa (Malibu, Calif.)
Langdon and Wilson Architects
IA10019
352 Linear Feet (approximately 145 boxes, 12 flat files, and 47 architectural models)
The records comprise architectural drawings and renderings, models, design research materials, construction administration records, photographs, and electronic files documenting the design and construction of the Getty Villa and Ranch House renovation from 1994-2004. The records were created by Machado and Silvetti Associates and serve as an overview and summary of the project.
Biographical Information: Machado and Silvetti Associates
Machado and Silvetti Associates is an architecture and urban design firm based in Boston, MA. Incorporated in 1985, the firm's diverse projects include art museums, educational institutions, and urban design and planning worldwide.
In 1991, the firm was given the first ever Award in Architecture by the American Academy of Arts and Letters. The office has since received three National Honor Awards from the American Institute of Architects as well as the AIA Brick in Architecture Award, ten Progressive Architecture awards and citations, twelve design awards from the New England AIA chapter, seventeen Boston Society of Architects awards, including the 2003 Harleston Parker Medal, and the International Award for Architecture in Stone.
The firm's designs have been published in numerous international professional magazines and displayed in exhibitions in the United States, Europe, and Latin America. Monographs produced on the firm include,Rodolfo Machado and Jorge Silvetti: Buildings for Cities (1990),Casas 40: Rodolfo Machado & Jorge Silvetti (1995), and Unprecedented Realism: The Architecture of Machado and Silvetti (1995).
The J. Paul Getty Trust commissioned Machado and Silvetti Associates for the master plan and design of the new expansion of the Getty Villa after an extensive international search.
Historical Background: The Getty Villa
The Getty Villa, located in Malibu, California, operates as a museum and educational center dedicated to the study of the arts and cultures of ancient Greece, Rome, and Etruria. The Getty Villa was designed to house J. Paul Getty's art collection when the collection outgrew his Ranch House, which had served as a private museum since 1954. After considering various options for expanding the Ranch House, Getty decided in the fall of 1968 to build a new museum on the same property, in the form of a first-century Roman country house, based primarily on the plans of the ancient Villa dei Papiri just outside of Herculaneum. The archaeologist Norman Neuerburg, who had studied the ruins of Herculaneum and was an authority on Roman domestic architecture, was retained as a consultant for the project. The Santa Monica architectural firm Langdon & Wilson was hired to design the Villa, and British architect Stephen Garrett, who had served as Getty's consultant in the remodeling of a Getty home in Posillipo, Italy, was retained as overseer of the construction. Landscape architect Emmet Wemple designed the gardens, Garth Benton worked on the murals, and Bruce Ptolomy worked on the fountains. Construction began on December 21, 1970, and the new museum opened to the public on January 16, 1974, receiving negative and positive reviews.
J. Paul Getty died in 1976 without ever seeing the museum he commissioned, but is buried at the Villa site on a bluff overlooking the ocean. After Getty's death and the establishment of the J. Paul Getty Trust, the Villa became part of a larger vision. As part of the J. Paul Getty Museum, the Villa is overseen by the J. Paul Getty Trust, an international cultural and philanthropic organization serving both general audiences and specialized professionals. The Trust is a not-for-profit institution, educational in purpose and character, that focuses on the visual arts in all of their dimensions. As of 2011 the Trust supports and oversees four programs: the Getty Research Institute; the Getty Foundation; the Getty Conservation Institute; and the J. Paul Getty Museum. Beginning in the 1980s the Trust developed an expansion plan that included the Getty Center campus in Brentwood and the renovation and expansion of the Villa in Malibu. When the Getty Center opened in 1997, the Villa closed to undergo extensive remodeling.
The architectural firm of Machado and Silvetti Associates redesigned the Villa site, adding galleries, skylights, an auditorium, an amphitheater, and new structures for conservation and administrative offices. Much of the original Villa was retained, including the wall murals, which original artist Garth Benton agreed to restore and refresh. The redesigned Villa opened on January 28, 2006, receiving high praise from reviewers. While most of the Museum's collections are housed at the Getty Center, the antiquities collection is housed at the Villa. The Getty Villa serves a varied audience through its permanent collection, changing exhibitions, conservation, scholarship, research, and public programs in an intimate setting overlooking the Pacific Ocean. Public and scholarly programs at the Villa include lectures, seminars, conferences, workshops, symposia, film series, musical concerts, and theatrical performances in the Barbara and Lawrence Fleischman Outdoor Classical Theater.
Scope and Contents of Collection
The collection comprises architectural drawings and renderings, models, design research materials, construction administration records, photographs, and electronic files created by Machado and Silvetti Associates documenting the design and construction of the Getty Villa and Ranch House renovation project from 1994-2004.
Series III, the project planning and administration records, primarily reflect the files of Machado and Silvetti associates Peter Lofgren (Associate in charge of the Masterplan Team, 1993-1996, Contracts and Entitlements Manager, 1996-unknown) and Tim Love (Associate in charge of the Masterplan Team, 1993-1996, Project Manager and Senior Designer, 1996-2002) dating from 1993-2001. They consist of administrative files, blueline prints, blueprints, black-and-white prints, and drawings.
The records in Series III serve as an overview and summary of the project phases and include materials relating to associate architect and consultant selection, the space program and master plan, entitlements, budget and administrative issues. Also included are reference logs and subject files that provide a more detailed look at certain portions of the project.
Related Archival Materials Note
The following materials are offered as possible sources of further information on the people and subjects covered by the records. The listing is not exhaustive.
Getty Institutional Archives
Getty Villa photographs, Julius Shulman. The Getty Research Institute (IA20031).
Design competition sketchbooks for the Getty Villa renovation, 1993, J. Paul Getty Trust. The Getty Research Institute (2005.IA.07).
Getty Villa construction records, 1960, 1964, 1968-1986, undated, J. Paul Getty Museum. The Getty Research Institute (IA10001).
Conditions Governing Access
The records described in accession 2004.IA.06 are available for use by qualified researchers.
The records in accessions 2004.IA.05 and 2013.IA.36, subject to review for permanently closed information, are open to qualified researchers. Requests for access will be reviewed on a case-by-case basis.
The following types of records are permanently closed: records containing personal information, records that compromise security or operations, legal communications, legal work product, and records related to donors. The J. Paul Getty Trust reserves the right to restrict access to any records held by the Institutional Archives.
Arrangement
The records are roughly arranged into three series:
Series I. Drawings and sketches, 1994-2000
Series II. Models, 1995-2000
Series III. Project planning and administration, 1993-2001.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
The materials described in this finding aid originated in accession 2004.IA.05 and 2004.IA.06, which were transferred to the Archives by the creators, Machado and Silvetti Associates. Accession 2013.IA.36 was later transferred to the Archives from Capital Project Support.
Museum architecture -- California; Museum buildings -- California -- Malibu -- Design and construction; Art museums -- Design and construction; Architectural drawings -- 20th century; Architectural records; Architectural models; Architecture -- Roman influences; Museum buildings -- Planning; Machado and Silvetti Associates, Inc; J. Paul Getty Museum; Getty Villa (Malibu, Calif.); Langdon and Wilson Architects
- Drawings and sketches, 1994-2000; Series I.
  - Master plan archival studies, museum existing conditions, Fall 1994; (ink on mylar) (Box 2004.IA.06 - 1)
  - Design sketches, Fall 1994 (Box 2004.IA.06 - 2)
  - Photographic negatives of sketchbooks and drawings, circa 1994; (13 color negatives) (Box 2004.IA.06-119)
  - Presentation/original renderings, September 7, 1994 (Box 2004.IA.06 - 3)
  - Presentation/original renderings, October 25, 1994 (Box 2004.IA.06 - 4)
  - Presentation/original renderings, November 30, 1994 (Box 2004.IA.06 - 5)
  - Presentation/original renderings, November 30, 1994 (Box 2004.IA.06 - 6)
  - Presentation/originals, January 4, 1995 (Box 2004.IA.06 - 7)
  - Presentation/originals, February 1995 (Box 2004.IA.06 - 8)
  - Kelly Wilson original renderings and studies, September 1995 (Box 2004.IA.06 - 9)
  - Original drawings and renderings, site sections, and site plans, March 13, 1995 (Box 2004.IA.06 - 10)
  - Original drawings and renderings, site plans and site sections [the next box in the chronology is 37], April 11, 1995 (Box 2004.IA.06 - 11)
  - Original drawings and copies, January 9, 1996 (Box 2004.IA.06 - 13)
  - Schematic design consultant's set; 175.0 and 194.0 pricking plans and vellum copy, February and March 11, 1996 (Box 2004.IA.06 - 14)
  - Entry Court studies A thru E plans, sections, and sketches, June 11, 1996 (Box 2004.IA.06 - 15)
  - Cafe/Auditorium and Entry Court plans and sections; NC schematic drawings 101-108 NC, 201 & 202 NC, July 11, 1996 (Box 2004.IA.06 - 16)
  - Entry Court/Loggia miscellaneous sketches, April 1995; June-July 1996 (Box 2004.IA.06 - 17)
  - South parking, September-October 1996 (Box 2004.IA.06 - 18)
  - Outdoor theater sketches, central plaza, March 1995; (1 of 2) (Box 2004.IA.06 - 19)
  - Outdoor theater sketches, D.D. studies, October 23, 1996; 1997; (2 of 2) (Box 2004.IA.06 - 20)
  - Bookstore/Cafe studies, pre D.D, 1996-1997; (1 of 2) (Box 2004.IA.06 - 21)
  - Bookstore/Cafe studies, pre-D.D., 1996-1997; (2 of 2) (Box 2004.IA.06 - 22)
  - Auditorium sketches, 1996-1997; (1 of 2) (Box 2004.IA.06 - 23)
  - Auditorium sketches, 1996-1997; (2 of 2) (Box 2004.IA.06 - 24)
  - Auditorium and outdoor theater, Tim Love, concept drawings "missing stones," strata wall, 1996 (Box 2004.IA.06 - 25)
  - Old parking structure studies, master planning phase, January 1995 (Box 2004.IA.06 - 26)
  - Masterplan sketches - Phase II studies, June 1995 (Box 2004.IA.06 - 27)
  - Sketchbook, research material for proposal, May 1, 1997 (Box 2004.IA.06 - 35)
  - Entitlements and plan drawings, 1995-1996 (Box 2004.IA.06 - 36)
  - Presentation original renderings [follows box 11 chronologically], May 17, 1995 (Box 2004.IA.06 - 37)
  - Schematic design set originals, May 15, 1996; (1 of 4) (Box 2004.IA.06 - 38)
  - Schematic design set originals, May 15, 1996; (2 of 4) (Box 2004.IA.06 - 39)
  - Schematic design set originals (first pricing set), May 15, 1996; (3 of 4) (Box 2004.IA.06 - 40)
  - Schematic design set originals (FF & E set), May 15, 1996; (4 of 4) (Box 2004.IA.06 - 41)
  - Schematic design set, 100% vellum set [compare boxes 42-43 with 38-41], May 15, 1996; (1 of 2) (Box 2004.IA.06 - 42)
  - Schematic design set, 100% vellum set, May 15, 1996; (2 of 2) (Box 2004.IA.06 - 43)
  - Presentation, original line drawings, xerox on vellum set, original renderings, June 20, 1995 (Box 2004.IA.06 - 44)
  - Presentation, underlays for final drawings (some copies), September 7, 1995 (Box 2004.IA.06 - 45)
  - Presentation original ink drawings (exhibition material), September 7, 1995 (Box 2004.IA.06 - 46)
  - Presentation xerox on vellum set, 11"x17" xerox set, September 7, 1995 (Box 2004.IA.06 - 47)
  - Presentation original drawings, October 31; November 10,; December 12, 1995 (Box 2004.IA.06 - 48)
  - Presentation, original drawings, model sepia, January 9, 1996 (Box 2004.IA.06 - 49)
  - Presentation, original drawings, original renderings, February 13, 1996 (Box 2004.IA.06 - 50)
  - Original drawings, 100% vellum set, October 23, 1996 (Box 2004.IA.06 - 51)
  - Progress set, originals, vellum + 1 blue, November 22, 1996 (Box 2004.IA.06 - 52)
  - Originals, 100% vellum set, new construction and Museum, pre-D.D. drawings, February 11; March 1997 (Box 2004.IA.06 - 53)
  - Getty Villa Sketchbook [did this get removed and put in a different accession??] (Box 2004.IA.06 - 54)
  - Presentation, xerox on Vellum Set (see also box 45), August 1, 1995 (Box 2004.IA.06 - 55)
  - Presentation, plan revisions to April 15 schematic design set (see boxes 38 to 41), May 14, 1996 (Box 2004.IA.06 - 56)
  - Original line drawings, xerox on vellum set, base model sepia (see box 37), May 17, 1995 (Box 2004.IA.06 - 57)
  - User meeting mark-ups, slope change mark-ups and miscellaneous design drawings, November 4, 1996 (Box 2004.IA.06 - 58)
  - DD drawings sent to users and user comments (Box 2004.IA.06 - 59)
  - Getty Villa new construction: Full 100% DD set (record set), March 30, 1999 Full bid set (record set), April 15, 1996 100% schematic design set (1 vellum set, 1 blueprint set); Getty Villa: March 17, 2000 North Campus 25% DD (Repricing) set (1/2 size record copy), January 28, 2000 North Campus 25% DD set (1/2 size record copy), August 1, 2000 North Campus 100% SD set (1/2 size record copy), August 18, 2000 North Campus 100% DD set (1/2 size record copy), December 15, 1999 Bid set - Addendum D: New Construction, December 15, 1999 Bid set - Addendum D: Ranch House, December 15, 1999 Bid set - Addendum D: Museum, February 15, 2000 North Campus CD 1/2 size Progress Print (status of set prior to Machado and Silvetti CD production) (Box 2004.IA.06 - 61)
  - Museum basement, Ranch House technical drawings [evaluate to discard], November 1996-January 1997 (Box 2004.IA.06 - 63)
  - Entitlements, B&E Drawings, civil engineers (Box 2004.IA.06 - 64)
  - Entitlements, site plan underlays and plot plans (Box 2004.IA.06 - 65)
  - DD Ranch House, schematic design (see box 58), March 22, 1996 (Box 2004.IA.06 - 66)
  - Entitlements, Section Drawings, October; December 1995 (Box 2004.IA.06 - 67)
  - LW Museum check set with MSA comments, November 20, 1998 (Box 2004.IA.06 - 68A-C)
  - Signage design sketches, 1998-2000 (Box 2004.IA.06 - 69)
  - Watercolor renderings by Max Driven (Machado and Silvetti employee), 1997-1998 (Box 2004.IA.06 - [70, 72, 102])
  - Museum gallery "Color Studies" (important for archival material - instrumental in the development of color schemes for the galleries), 1997 (Box 2004.IA.06 - 71)
  - Master planning watercolors, January 4, 1995 (Box 2004.IA.06 - [70, 72, 102])
  - Entitlements, CUP exhibit, graphic material, 1996-1998 (Box 2004.IA.06 - 73)
  - Five original pastel/Prismacolor on mylar renderings of the West Campus and Museum - Trustee Presentation material (Renderings by Kelly Wilson, MSA consultant), September 1995; Bankers box (Box 2004.IA.06 - 74)
  - "Before and After" photos and renderings, photos and color copies of Kelly Wilson drawings mounted on foamcore, September 1995 (Box 2004.IA.06 - 75)
  - Computer drawings on mylar and original pencil on vellum site section (important drawing) produced for April 1997 article in Architecture Magazine (Box 2004.IA.06 - 76)
  - Master plan original perspectives, final renderings and draft underlays (pencil on vellum by Conrad Ello), 1995-1996 (Box 2004.IA.06 - 77)
  - Construction documents for west campus full-scale mock-ups, 1998 (Box 2004.IA.06 - 78)
  - Entitlements material, 1996-1998 (Box 2004.IA.06 - 79)
  - Entitlements material, 1996-1998 (Box 2004.IA.06 - 80)
  - Entitlements material, 1996-1998 (Box 2004.IA.06 - 81)
  - Bronze window wall studies, 1998-1999 (Box 2004.IA.06 - 82)
  - Outdoor theater redesign studies and bookstore redesign studies, 2001-2002 (Box 2004.IA.06 - 83)
  - Outdoor theater design studies, 1997-2000 (Box 2004.IA.06 - 84)
  - Entry court design studies, 1997-1998 (Box 2004.IA.06 - 85)
  - West campus original renderings, including prismacolor original site plan, 1997-1998 (Box 2004.IA.06 - 86)
  - Auditorium design studies, 1997-1998 (Box 2004.IA.06 - 87)
  - Cafe/West Campus design studies, 1997-1998 (Box 2004.IA.06 - 88)
  - "Strata Wall" West Campus exterior wall studies, 1997-1998 (Box 2004.IA.06 - 89)
  - Central plant design studies, 1996-1999 (Box 2004.IA.06 - 90)
  - North campus design studies, 1998-2000 (Box 2004.IA.06 - 92)
  - Early North campus design studies, 1997 (Box 2004.IA.06 - 93)
  - Full-size vellum set - Langdon and Wilson construction documents (set is incomplete - confer with Langdon Wilson to acquire complete set), 1974 (Box 2004.IA.06 - 94)
  - Full-size vellum set - Langdon and Wilson construction documents (set is incomplete - confer with Langdon Wilson to acquire complete set), 1974 (Box 2004.IA.06 - 95)
  - Exhibition cases design studies, 1998-1999; (1 of 6) (Box 2004.IA.06 - 96)
  - Exhibition cases design studies, 1998-1999; (2 of 6) (Box 2004.IA.06 - 97)
  - Exhibition cases design studies, 1998-1999; (3 of 6) (Box 2004.IA.06 - 98)
  - Exhibition cases design studies, 1998-1999; (4 of 6) (Box 2004.IA.06 - 99)
  - Exhibition cases design studies, 1998-1999; (5 of 6) (Box 2004.IA.06 - 100)
  - Exhibition cases design studies, 1998-1999; (6 of 6) (Box 2004.IA.06 - 101)
  - 12" x 15" flat folio w/Museum watercolor renderings, 1996-1997 (Box 2004.IA.06 - [70, 72, 102])
  - Museum design studies, 1997-1998 (Box 2004.IA.06 - 103)
  - North Campus design studies, 1998-2000 (Box 2004.IA.06 - 104)
  - North Campus design studies, 1998-2000 (Box 2004.IA.06 - 105)
  - South Parking garage design studies, 1999 (Box 2004.IA.06 - 106)
  - Untitled set of blueline prints (site plan, Ranch House, Conservation Court), January 26, 1996 (Flatfile 2013.IA.36-1)
  - Schematic Design Consultant Set (blueline prints), March 11, 1996 (Flatfile 2013.IA.36-1)
  - Getty Explore Store (blueline prints "drawn by Pawel"), December 2004 (Flatfile 2013.IA.36-1)
  - 1996 Trustee presentation watercolors, box 3 of 7 (Box 2004.IA.06-142)
  - Perspective view of entry court entrance watercolor, undated (Flatfile 2004.IA.06-146)
  - Unnumbered mounted color drawing of Villa, undated (Flatfile 2004.IA.06-147)
  - Untitled, undated (Flatfile 2004.IA.06-148)
- Models, 1995-2000; Series II.
  - Master planning: Master plan site model of full build-out (Phases 1 and 2), March 11, 1995; (18' x 18' x8" (h)) (Model 2004.IA.06 - Model 1)
  - Master planning: Master plan 2-piece sectional model (1 of 2), May 13, 1995; (18" x 7'-0" x 14" (h), 1/16"=1'-0") (Model 2004.IA.06 - Model 2)
  - Master planning: Master plan 2-piece site sectional model (2 of 2), May 13, 1995; (24" x 7'-0" x 15" (h), 1/16"=1'-0") (Model 2004.IA.06 - Model 3)
  - West Campus: Entry court study model - early schematic design, December 15, 1995; (15" x 14" x 10" (h), 1/16"=1'-0") (Model 2004.IA.06 - Model 4)
  - West Campus: Entry court study model - early schematic design, December 12, 1995; (13" x 14" x 10" (h), 1/4"=1'-0") (Model 2004.IA.06 - Model 5)
  - West Campus: Entry court model - early schematic design, December 15, 1995; 18" x 18" x 11"(h), 1/4"=1'-0") (Model 2004.IA.06 - Model 6)
  - West Campus: Entry court study model - early schematic design, December 12, 1995; (14" x 24" x 12"(h), 1/4"=1'-0") (Model 2004.IA.06 - Model 7)
  - West Campus: Cafe-Auditorium, 2-piece model (1 of 2) with removable basswood pieces, January 7, 1996; Note: the basswood pieces are significantly damaged.; (24" x 30" x 12"(h), 1/8"=1'-0") (Model 2004.IA.06 - Model 8)
  - West Campus: Cafe-Auditorium, 2-piece model (2 of 2) with removable pieces, January 7, 1996; (TBD) (Model 2004.IA.06 - Model 9)
  - West Campus: Entry court model, January 15, 1996; 16" x 22" x 10"(h), 1/4"=1'-0") (Model 2004.IA.06 -Model 10)
  - West Campus: Cafe-Auditorium, 2-piece model (1 of 2), March 10, 1996; (17" x 24" x 11"(h), 1/8"=1'-0") (Model 2004.IA.06 -Model 11)
    General
    Note: appears to be a later version of model #9
  - West Campus: Entry court study model - schematic design, June 8, 1996; (24" x 30" x 16"(h), 1/4"=1'-0") (Model 2004.IA.06 -Model 12)
  - South Parking: Camper lot garage- schematic model of a split, 3-level garage scheme (i.e. bifurcated scheme"), circa January 1997; (30" x 42" x 18"(h), 1/32"=1'-0") (Model 2004.IA.06 -Model 13)
  - North Campus: Office building facade detail study model, circa 2000; (14" x 18" 4"(h), NTS) (Model 2004.IA.06 -Model 14)
  - North Campus: (US art box 24), circa late 1990s; (23.5" x 29.5" x 18") (Model 2004.IA.06-Model 14a)
  - West Campus: Large Theater, March 1996; (35" x 33" x 14") (Model 2004.IA.06-Model 14b)
  - West Campus: Auditorium model, January 1996; (16" x 22" x 10", 1/8"=1'-0") (Model 2004.IA.06-Model 14c)
  - West Campus: Cafe studies, circa late-1990s (Model 2004.IA.06-Model 14d)
  - Museum/South Parking: Study models, circa late 1990s; (16" x 25" x 10") (Model 2004.IA.06-Model 14e)
  - West Campus: Entry court, June 8, 1996; (27" x 10" x 7") (Model 2004.IA.06-Model 14f)
  - Master Planning: Master plan site model of full build-out (Phases 1 and 2), March 11, 1995; (51.5" x 32" x 18.5", 1" = 40'-0") (Model 2004.IA.06 -Model 15)
    Note: Originally included a 3'-high birch veneer plywood podium on casters with plexiglass case.
  - Master Planning: Master plan "plug-in" feature element (irregular shape) for models 2 and 3, May 13, 1995; (21" x 14" 5"(h), 1/16"=1'-0") (Model 2004.IA.06 -Model 16)
  - West Campus: Bronze window wall detail study, painted wood, circa 1998; (NA, small) (Model 2004.IA.06 -model 17)
  - Ranch House: Casework detail studies, circa 1998; (NA, small) (Model 2004.IA.06-Model 18a)
  - Ranch House: Casework detail studies, circa 1998; (NA, small) (Model 2004.IA.06-Model 18b)
  - Museum: Exhibition casework labeling/signage details, circa 1998; (N/A, small) (Model 2004.IA.06-Model 19a)
  - Museum: Exhibition casework labeling/signage details, circa 1998; (N/A, small) (Model 2004.IA.06-Model 19b)
  - North Campus: North campus site model, October 16, 1999; (24" x 24" x 9"(h), 1/16"=1'-0") (Model 2004.IA.06 -Model 20)
  - North Campus: Detail section model of office building, May 13, 2000; (32" x 7" x14.5"(h), 3/8"=1'-0") (Model 2004.IA.06 -Model 21)
  - North Campus: Detail section model of antiquities conservation lab building, May 13, 2000; (32" x 9" x 10"(h), 3/8"=1'-0") (Model 2004.IA.06 -Model 22)
  - West Campus: Entry court study model, circa 1999; (24" x 15" x 15") (Model 2004.IA.06-Model 22a)
  - North Campus: detail section model of GCI facility, May 13, 2000; (32" x?, 3/8" = 1'-0") (One of three - see models 21 and 22 above) (Model 2004.IA.06 -model 23)
  - West Campus, December 7, 1996; (3/8" = 1'-0") (Model 2004.IA.06 -model 24)
  - Entry pavilion "model A,", February 12, 1996; (37 x 20 x 22) (Model 2004.IA.06 -model 25)
  - Entry pavilion "model A,", February 12, 1996; (22 x 21 x 11) (Model 2004.IA.06 -model 26)
  - Entry pavilion "model A,", February 12, 1996; (22 x 16 x 13) (Model 2004.IA.06 -model 27)